Vamshi Vanguri

Vamshi.xyz github.com/vamshi1020 linkedin.com/in/vamshi1020

Summary

Successful and Outgoing Certified Amazon Cloud, Cisco Network engineer with 3+ years of experience in specialized networking and amazon cloud services. Excited to leverage my technical and professional expertise to explore the programming world as a Full-stack Software Developer.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3. Frameworks/Libraries: Bootstrap, AngularJS, React.

Other: Git/GitHub, AWS Cloud, AZURE, Cisco Networking, RDBMS.

Project Experience

Log Analysis - https://vamshi1020.github.io/log-analysis/

August 2017

- Created a reporting tool that can print reports based on newspaper database.
- Used Python3, Vagrant and Virtual Box to connect database.
- Coded in Python for formatted output and ran it through PostgreSQL by creating VIEWS.

Portfolio Website - https://vamshi1020.github.io/FSND2-Portfolio/

April 2017

- Single-page, responsive portfolio website built with **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript** and **bootstrap** frameworks.
- Coded the complete website to be fully responsive across various mobiles, Desktops and Laptops.
- Used breakpoints by using **Flexbox**.

Movie-Trailer Website - https://vamshi1020.github.io/Udacity-Movie-Trailer-website/

March 2017

- Built a website that plays trailers of popular movies, while allowing users to star their favourites.
- Used **Python** in back-end, **HTML**, **CSS** and **JavaScript** in front-end.
- Wrote code in Python and ran it through Tomatoes file provided by Udacity.

Work Experience

DATA_PIONEER – Network Engineer

New York, NY | December 2016-Present

- Worked with Cisco Routers and switches.
- Worked and learned a great deal from AWS cloud services and AZURE cloud.
- Monitored and troubleshot LAN and WAN network traffic.

TRU-SOFT SOLUTIONS. - Systems Engineer

Jacksonville, FL | July 2016-November 2016

- Experienced with protocols like RIP, EIGRP, OSPF and BGP.
- Worked on Remedy Ticketing tool for maintenances and traffic logs.
- Responsible for installing and supporting hardware and applications on PC.

VISATCHA - System Admin/Engineer

Hyderabad, India | May 2012-November 2014

- Designed IP addresses, subnetting and routing on different devices in network.
- Established new user accounts/logins and permissions for users.
- Managed Local Area network.

Education

Udacity – Full-Stack Web Developer Nanodegree Oklahoma Christian University, OK- Master's in Engineering, M.S. JNT University, Hyderabad, India. – Electrical Engineering, B.Tech March 2017-Present April 2016 May2012

Honors and Activities

- Capilibrium Solutions –Stealth Mode AI Startup Founder
- AWS SA Associate.
- CCNA R&S

May 2017 - Present

March 2017 - Present

Aug 2016 - Present